<PolymerNanocomposite>
    <ID>L271_S24_Sun_2004</ID>
    <DATA_SOURCE>
        <Citation>
            <CommonFields>
                <CitationType>research article</CitationType>
                <Publication>Journal of Polymer Science</Publication>
                <Title>Glass Transition and Relaxation Behavior of Epoxy Nanocomposites</Title>
                <Author>Sun, Y.</Author>
                <Author>Zhang, Z.</Author>
                <Author>Moon, K. S.</Author>
                <Author>Wong, C. P.</Author>
                <Keyword>composites</Keyword>
                <Keyword>dielectric properties</Keyword>
                <Keyword>glass transition</Keyword>
                <Keyword>interfaces</Keyword>
                <Keyword>nanoparticles</Keyword>
                <Keyword>thermomechanical properties</Keyword>
                <Publisher>Wiley Periodicals, Inc.</Publisher>
                <PublicationYear>2004</PublicationYear>
                <DOI>10.1002/polb.20251</DOI>
                <Volume>42</Volume>
                <URL>www.interscience.wiley.com</URL>
                <DateOfCitation>08/09/2017</DateOfCitation>
            </CommonFields>
        </Citation>
    </DATA_SOURCE>
    <MATERIALS>
        <Matrix>
            <MatrixComponent>
                <ChemicalName>diglycidyl ether of bisphenol F</ChemicalName>
                <ManufacturerName>Resolution Performance Products</ManufacturerName>
                <TradeName>Epon 862</TradeName>
                <Hardener>hexahydro-4-methylphthalic anhydride</Hardener>
            </MatrixComponent>
            <MatrixProcessing>
                <ChooseParameter>
                    <Additive>
                        <Description>The hardener was HMPA. The weight ratio of the epoxy to the hardener was 1:0.83.</Description>
                        <Additive>hexahydro-4-methylphthalic anhydride</Additive>
                    </Additive>
                </ChooseParameter>
                <ChooseParameter>
                    <Additive>
                        <Description>2E4MZ-CN was used as the catalyst, and the concentration was 2.5 wt % with respect to the epoxy and hardener mixture.</Description>
                        <Additive>1-cyanoethyl- 2-ethyl-4-methylimidazole</Additive>
                    </Additive>
                </ChooseParameter>
                <ChooseParameter>
                    <Mixing>
                        <ChemicalUsed>epoxy</ChemicalUsed>
                        <ChemicalUsed>hardner</ChemicalUsed>
                        <ChemicalUsed>catalyst</ChemicalUsed>
                    </Mixing>
                </ChooseParameter>
            </MatrixProcessing>
        </Matrix>
        <Filler>
            <FillerComponent>
                <ChemicalName>aluminum</ChemicalName>
                <ManufacturerName>AlfaAesor</ManufacturerName>
                <ParticleSize>
                    <value>100</value>
                    <unit>nm</unit>
                </ParticleSize>
            </FillerComponent>
            <FillerComposition>
                <mass>0.45</mass>
            </FillerComposition>
        </Filler>
    </MATERIALS>
    <PROCESSING>
        <SolutionProcessing>
            <ChooseParameter>
                <Mixing>
                    <Description>the nanosized aluminum was hand-mixed for 30 min</Description>
                    <Time>
                        <value>30</value>
                        <unit>minutes</unit>
                    </Time>
                </Mixing>
            </ChooseParameter>
        </SolutionProcessing>
    </PROCESSING>
    <CHARACTERIZATION>
        <Dynamic_Mechanical_Analysis>
            <Equipment>model 2980, TA Instruments</Equipment>
            <Description>The dynamic mechanical properties of the epoxy&#8211; silica composites were evaluated after the samples were cured in a convection oven at 150 &#176;C for 1 h. The cured samples were cut into a strip (18 mm  6 mm 3 mm). A dynamic mechanical analyzer (model 2980, TA Instruments) was used to measure the dynamic moduli of the samples. The test was performed in a single-cantilever mode from 120 to 200 &#176;C at a heating rate of 3 &#176;C/min. Liquid nitrogen was used for the lowtemperature testing. The amplitude applied to the samples in the experiments was 15 m and resulted in a strain level of around 0.5%, which was within the linear viscoelastic region of the epoxy. The storage modulus and loss modulus of the samples were calculated with the preinstalled software. Tg also could be obtained from the peak position of the loss modulus.</Description>
        </Dynamic_Mechanical_Analysis>
        <Dielectric_and_Impedance_Spectroscopy_Analysis>
            <Equipment>model 2970, TA Instruments</Equipment>
            <Description>The dielectric properties of the epoxy&#8211;silica composite were measured with a dielectric analyzer (model 2970, TA Instruments). The single-surface sensor was used for the dielectric analysis (DEA) experiments. The uncured liquid resin was coated on the sensor and cured with the same conditions used for the dynamic mechanical analysis (DMA) samples. The DEA experiments were performed from 35 to 250 &#176;C with a stepping temperature of 5 &#176;C and a frequency sweep varying logarithmically from 0.01 to 100,000 Hz. The dielectric perpermittivity and dielectric loss factor were calculated with the preinstalled software.</Description>
        </Dielectric_and_Impedance_Spectroscopy_Analysis>
        <Differential_Scanning_Calorimetry>
            <Equipment>model Q1000, TA Instruments</Equipment>
            <Description>The curing behavior and Tg&#8217;s of the epoxy composites were characterized with a modulated differential scanning calorimeter (model Q1000, TA Instruments). A sample of approximately 10 mg was sealed in a hermetic aluminum pan. Dynamic scanning experiments were conducted at a ramp rate of 5 &#176;C/min, from the ambient temperature to 250 &#176;C, to obtain the curing heat-flow diagram of the composite. The cured sample was left in the differential scanning calorimetry (DSC) cell and cooled to room temperature. Then, the sample was reheated to 200 &#176;C at 5 &#176;C/min with a temperature modulation of +/-1 &#176;C/min to obtain the second heat-flow diagram. From the step change of the reversible heat flow of the second diagram, Tg was determined.</Description>
            <HeatingRate>
                <value>5</value>
                <unit>deg C / min</unit>
            </HeatingRate>
        </Differential_Scanning_Calorimetry>
    </CHARACTERIZATION>
    <PROPERTIES>
        <Viscoelastic>null</Viscoelastic>
        <Thermal>
            <GlassTransitionTemperature>
                <value>106.888307</value>
                <unit>Celsius</unit>
            </GlassTransitionTemperature>
        </Thermal>
    </PROPERTIES>
</PolymerNanocomposite>
    